<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World! on PORTFOLIO</title>
    <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello World! on PORTFOLIO</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who has been vaccinated?</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_0/</guid>
      <description>We will visualize population vaccinated percentages on a map and forecast when countries should be expected to have vaccinated all citizens.
  The data will be sourced from the Oxford Martin School project of Covid-19 data collection. We use Microsoft SQL Server to query the global Covid-19 data and visualize the queries in Tableau.
  Jump to Interactive Visualization    PROJECT LINKS
Dataset: https://ourworldindata.org/covid-deaths</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard apps with Plotly</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_5/</guid>
      <description>Plotly&amp;rsquo;s Python graphing library makes interactive, publication-quality graphs
 MRI scan analysis   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer Costs: A Deep Learning Approach</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_4/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project is to propose an effective neural network model to better predict end of life claim costs for terminal cancer patients in South Africa that improves on what traditional linear models can achieve for the task.
  Palliative care is a medical treatment approach that improves the quality of life of patients and their families facing the problems associated with life-threatening illness, through the prevention and relief of suffering by means of early identification and impeccable assessment and treatment of pain and other problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Bitcoin data</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_4/</guid>
      <description>Since the launch of Bitcoin in 2008, hundreds of similar projects based on the blockchain technology have emerged. We call these cryptocurrencies (also coins or cryptos in the Internet slang). Some are extremely valuable nowadays, and others may have the potential to become extremely valuable in the future1. In fact, on the 6th of December of 2017, Bitcoin has a market capitalization above $200 billion.
 Astonishing increase of Bitcoin markert cap   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Analysis for Portfolio Selection</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_1/</guid>
      <description>We implement a hierarchical risk parity portfolio (LdP2016) for assets to explore the use of cluster analysis for portfolio constructive and compare this with standard mean-variance methods.
  The data will be sourced from Bloomberg. We will attempt to combine the HRP portfolio with the mean-variance portfolio using the Historical Simulation with Flexible Probabilities (HS-FP) framework developed by Meucci(M2010).
  Theoretical Proficiencies:
Stochastic processes, optimization theory, portfolio theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Netflix movies</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_3/</guid>
      <description>What started as a British mockumentary series about office culture in 2001 has since spawned ten other variants across the world, including an Israeli version (2010-13), a Hindi version (2019-), and even a French Canadian variant (2006-2007). Of all these iterations (including the original), the American series has been the longest-running, spanning 201 episodes over nine seasons.
In this notebook, we will take a look at a dataset of The Office episodes, and try to understand how the popularity and quality of the series varied over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep the Heart Unwrinkled</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_3/</guid>
      <description>This paper estimates the effect of old age pension on South African adult life satisfaction across four races, namely African, Coloured, Indian-Asian and White using the NIDS Wave 5 2017 dataset.
  Multiple linear regression was used to estimate the effect of explanatory variables on life satisfaction. The observed results are limited to the simplified techniques used in regression analysis.
  The paper finds receipt of pension to have an economically insignificant decrease in life satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive plots with Boker</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_2/</guid>
      <description>Bokeh is a Python library for creating interactive visualizations for modern web browsers. It helps you build beautiful graphics, ranging from simple plots to complex dashboards with streaming datasets. With Bokeh, you can create JavaScript-powered visualizations.
 Interactive Bokeh widget   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Package for the Analysis of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_5/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks provide a flexible basis for constructing non-linear models of real-world phenomena. Indeed, in recent times the model class has become an extremely popular tool amongst applied scientists owing both to its performance over a wide range of statistical tasks as well as the air of sentience that surrounds the internal functioning of the class—the result of well chosen metaphors for describing the basic mathematical operations that define it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing using WordCloud</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_1/</guid>
      <description>What is WordCloud?
Many times you might have seen a cloud filled with lots of words in different sizes, which represent the frequency or the importance of each word. This is called Tag Cloud or WordCloud. For this tutorial, you will learn how to create a WordCloud of your own in Python and customize it as you see fit. This tool will be quite handy for exploring text data and making your report more lively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensor Data, A Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/post/project_2/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to explore sensor data from industrial scraping machines.
Sensor are frequently attached to industrial machines, with the aim of inferring or modelling the machine performance. [&amp;hellip;updating&amp;hellip;]
link to Project GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email (mutsemitinotenda@gmail.com) or direct message me on these platforms.
   Platform Link     LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/tinotenda-mutsemi-2a107316b   Upwork: https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/~016b639211c8bb377e/   Git: https://github.com/TinotendaMutsemi   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/tinotendamutsemi   Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/tino_mutsemi/    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
