<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SKILLS on PORTIFOLIO HOME</title>
    <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SKILLS on PORTIFOLIO HOME</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Netflix movies</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_3/</guid>
      <description>What started as a British mockumentary series about office culture in 2001 has since spawned ten other variants across the world, including an Israeli version (2010-13), a Hindi version (2019-), and even a French Canadian variant (2006-2007). Of all these iterations (including the original), the American series has been the longest-running, spanning 201 episodes over nine seasons.
In this notebook, we will take a look at a dataset of The Office episodes, and try to understand how the popularity and quality of the series varied over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive plots with Boker</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_2/</guid>
      <description>Bokeh is a Python library for creating interactive visualizations for modern web browsers. It helps you build beautiful graphics, ranging from simple plots to complex dashboards with streaming datasets. With Bokeh, you can create JavaScript-powered visualizations.
 Interactive Bokeh widget   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Bitcoin data</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_4/</guid>
      <description>Since the launch of Bitcoin in 2008, hundreds of similar projects based on the blockchain technology have emerged. We call these cryptocurrencies (also coins or cryptos in the Internet slang). Some are extremely valuable nowadays, and others may have the potential to become extremely valuable in the future1. In fact, on the 6th of December of 2017, Bitcoin has a market capitalization above $200 billion.
 Astonishing increase of Bitcoin markert cap   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard apps with Plotly</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_5/</guid>
      <description>Plotly&amp;rsquo;s Python graphing library makes interactive, publication-quality graphs
 MRI scan analysis   link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing using WordCloud</title>
      <link>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinotendamutsemi.github.io/Tino_Mutsemi_Portfolio/skill/tutorial_1/</guid>
      <description>What is WordCloud?
Many times you might have seen a cloud filled with lots of words in different sizes, which represent the frequency or the importance of each word. This is called Tag Cloud or WordCloud. For this tutorial, you will learn how to create a WordCloud of your own in Python and customize it as you see fit. This tool will be quite handy for exploring text data and making your report more lively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
